# Sentence 1
Excavators	O
recorded	O
Harappan	B-PER
pottery	B-ART
shards	O
in	O
trench	B-CON
5	I-CON
near	O
Harappa	B-LOC

# Sentence 2
Achaemenid	O
influence	O
is	O
noted	O
in	O
the	O
300	B-PER
BCE	I-PER
layers	I-PER

# Sentence 3
The	O
survey	O
covered	O
Mohenjo-daro	B-LOC
and	O
adjacent	O
settlements	O

# Sentence 4
Samples	O
showed	O
high	O
copper	B-MAT
content	O

# Sentence 5
Field	O
notes	O
mention	O
trench	B-CON
A	I-CON
as	O
the	O
primary	O
context	O

# Sentence 6
A	O
fragment	O
of	O
a	O
terracotta	B-ART
figurine	O
was	O
catalogued	O

# Sentence 7
Radiocarbon	O
dates	O
suggest	O
Late	B-PER
Harappan	I-PER
phase	I-PER

# Sentence 8
The	O
team	O
mapped	O
the	O
Indus	B-LOC
Valley	I-LOC
survey	I-LOC

# Sentence 9
Microscopic	O
analysis	O
identified	O
bronze	B-MAT
alloy	O

# Sentence 10
Excavation	O
records	O
list	O
burial	B-CON
2	I-CON
as	O
a	O
secondary	O
deposit	O

# Sentence 11
A	O
copper	B-ART
axe	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 12
Stratigraphy	O
places	O
this	O
find	O
in	O
the	O
Gupta	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 13
The	O
site	O
at	O
Dholavira	B-LOC
has	O
multiple	O
mounds	O

# Sentence 14
Residue	O
tests	O
detected	O
organic	O
residues	O
on	O
terracotta	B-MAT

# Sentence 15
Contextual	O
notes	O
refer	O
to	O
layer	B-CON
IV	I-CON

# Sentence 16
A	O
string	O
of	O
faience	B-ART
beads	O
was	O
recorded	O

# Sentence 17
Estimated	O
occupation	O
dates	O
range	O
from	O
2600	B-PER
BCE	I-PER
to	O
1900	O

# Sentence 18
Surface	O
survey	O
near	O
Rakhigarhi	B-LOC
yielded	O
shards	O

# Sentence 19
Metallurgical	O
reports	O
mention	O
tin	B-MAT
traces	O

# Sentence 20
The	O
excavation	O
team	O
noted	O
a	O
burnt	O
layer	B-CON

# Sentence 21
A	O
stone	B-ART
celt	O
was	O
measured	O

# Sentence 22
Ceramic	O
typology	O
is	O
consistent	O
with	O
Early	B-PER
Harappan	I-PER

# Sentence 23
The	O
archaeological	O
survey	O
mapped	O
Lothal	B-LOC

# Sentence 24
Thin-section	O
analysis	O
identified	O
quartz	B-MAT
grains	O

# Sentence 25
Field	O
journal	O
records	O
trench	B-CON
12	I-CON
as	O
a	O
wet	O
context	O

# Sentence 26
A	O
bronze	B-ART
mirror	O
was	O
listed	O

# Sentence 27
Pottery	O
styles	O
are	O
dated	O
to	O
the	O
Kushan	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 28
Remote	O
sensing	O
highlighted	O
the	O
Ghaggar	B-LOC
riverbed	I-LOC

# Sentence 29
Chemical	O
tests	O
showed	O
lead	B-MAT
contamination	O

# Sentence 30
The	O
report	O
describes	O
a	O
secondary	O
burial	B-CON

# Sentence 31
A	O
carved	B-ART
seal	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 32
Stratigraphic	O
correlation	O
links	O
this	O
horizon	O
to	O
the	O
Iron	B-PER
Age	I-PER

# Sentence 33
Excavators	O
noted	O
a	O
fortification	O
at	O
Kalibangan	B-LOC

# Sentence 35
The	O
context	O
sheet	O
labels	O
layer	B-CON
3	I-CON

# Sentence 36
A	O
bronze	B-ART
pin	O
was	O
found	O

# Sentence 37
Ceramic	O
phases	O
are	O
assigned	O
to	O
the	O
Post-Gupta	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 38
Field	O
teams	O
surveyed	O
the	O
Sutlej	B-LOC
floodplain	I-LOC

# Sentence 39
Elemental	O
analysis	O
detected	O
arsenic	B-MAT

# Sentence 40
The	O
excavation	O
log	O
records	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
collapse	O

# Sentence 41
A	O
copper	B-ART
pin	O
was	O
catalogued	O

# Sentence 42
Typological	O
comparison	O
places	O
this	O
assemblage	O
in	O
the	O
Early	B-PER
Historic	I-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 43
The	O
survey	O
mapped	O
Banawali	B-LOC

# Sentence 44
Petrographic	O
study	O
identified	O
shale	B-MAT

# Sentence 45
Context	O
notes	O
mention	O
a	O
burial	B-CON
pit	I-CON

# Sentence 46
A	O
terracotta	B-ART
bangle	O
was	O
recorded	O

# Sentence 47
Radiocarbon	O
calibration	O
gives	O
a	O
range	O
around	O
1500	B-PER
BCE	I-PER

# Sentence 48
The	O
excavation	O
mapped	O
the	O
Narmada	B-LOC
terrace	I-LOC

# Sentence 49
X-ray	O
fluorescence	O
detected	O
zinc	B-MAT

# Sentence 50
Field	O
notes	O
list	O
trench	B-CON
7	I-CON
as	O
sterile	O

# Sentence 51
A	O
stone	B-ART
bead	O
was	O
measured	O

# Sentence 52
Ceramic	O
sequence	O
is	O
assigned	O
to	O
the	O
Maurya	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 53
The	O
team	O
recorded	O
a	O
settlement	O
at	O
Ropar	B-LOC

# Sentence 54
Compositional	O
analysis	O
showed	O
silver	B-MAT
in	O
trace	O
amounts	O

# Sentence 55
The	O
context	O
form	O
notes	O
a	O
posthole	B-CON

# Sentence 56
A	O
carved	B-ART
terracotta	O
panel	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 57
Chronology	O
places	O
this	O
phase	O
in	O
the	O
Sunga	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 58
Geophysical	O
survey	O
identified	O
an	O
anomaly	O
near	O
Harappa	B-LOC

# Sentence 59
Metallography	O
revealed	O
copper	B-MAT
grain	O
structure	O

# Sentence 60
Excavation	O
notes	O
record	O
a	O
sealed	B-CON
deposit	I-CON

# Sentence 61
A	O
bronze	B-ART
figurine	O
was	O
listed	O

# Sentence 62
Typology	O
suggests	O
Late	B-PER
Harappan	I-PER
occupation	I-PER

# Sentence 63
The	O
survey	O
documented	O
Dholavira	B-LOC
mound	I-LOC

# Sentence 64
Elemental	O
spectra	O
showed	O
phosphorus	B-MAT

# Sentence 65
Contextual	O
records	O
note	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
edge	I-CON

# Sentence 66
A	O
polished	B-ART
stone	O
axe	O
was	O
catalogued	O

# Sentence 68
The	O
excavation	O
mapped	O
the	O
Ghazi	B-LOC
mound	I-LOC

# Sentence 69
Microscopic	O
residue	O
analysis	O
found	O
bitumen	B-MAT

# Sentence 70
Field	O
notes	O
describe	O
a	O
secondary	B-CON
fill	I-CON

# Sentence 71
A	O
copper	B-ART
amulet	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 72
Stratigraphy	O
links	O
this	O
horizon	O
to	O
the	O
Late	B-PER
Bronze	I-PER
Age	I-PER

# Sentence 73
The	O
survey	O
recorded	O
a	O
site	O
near	O
Sarnath	B-LOC

# Sentence 74
Petrographic	O
analysis	O
identified	O
sandstone	B-MAT

# Sentence 75
Context	O
sheets	O
note	O
a	O
burial	B-CON
cluster	I-CON

# Sentence 76
A	O
faience	B-ART
pendant	O
was	O
listed	O

# Sentence 77
Ceramic	O
phases	O
are	O
assigned	O
to	O
the	O
Chalcolithic	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 78
Remote	O
survey	O
mapped	O
the	O
Saraswati	B-LOC
course	I-LOC

# Sentence 79
XRF	O
analysis	O
detected	O
manganese	B-MAT

# Sentence 80
Excavation	O
logs	O
record	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
backfill	I-CON

# Sentence 81
A	O
carved	B-ART
seal	O
impression	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 82
Typological	O
comparison	O
dates	O
the	O
assemblage	O
to	O
the	O
Kushan	B-PER
era	I-PER

# Sentence 83
The	O
team	O
surveyed	O
the	O
Banawali	B-LOC
perimeter	I-LOC

# Sentence 84
Metallurgical	O
tests	O
showed	O
bronze	B-MAT
patination	O

# Sentence 85
Context	O
records	O
list	O
a	O
layer	B-CON
with	O
ash	O

# Sentence 88
The	O
excavation	O
mapped	O
a	O
settlement	O
at	O
Harappa	B-LOC

# Sentence 89
Microscopic	O
study	O
identified	O
hematite	B-MAT

# Sentence 90
Field	O
notes	O
describe	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
section	I-CON

# Sentence 91
A	O
bronze	B-ART
spearhead	O
was	O
recorded	O

# Sentence 92
Ceramic	O
sequence	O
is	O
linked	O
to	O
the	O
Early	B-PER
Historic	I-PER

# Sentence 93
The	O
survey	O
documented	O
Rakhigarhi	B-LOC
platform	I-LOC

# Sentence 94
Elemental	O
analysis	O
detected	O
cobalt	B-MAT

# Sentence 95
Context	O
forms	O
note	O
a	O
burial	B-CON
trench	I-CON

# Sentence 96
A	O
stone	B-ART
cutter	O
was	O
measured	O

# Sentence 97
Typology	O
places	O
this	O
assemblage	O
in	O
the	O
Gupta	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 98
Remote	O
sensing	O
identified	O
an	O
ancient	O
channel	O
near	O
Dholavira	B-LOC

# Sentence 99
Petrographic	O
study	O
showed	O
granite	B-MAT

# Sentence 100
Excavation	O
notes	O
record	O
a	O
sealed	B-CON
floor	I-CON

# Sentence 101
A	O
faience	B-ART
bead	O
was	O
catalogued	O

# Sentence 103
The	O
team	O
surveyed	O
the	O
Sutlej	B-LOC
terrace	I-LOC

# Sentence 104
Chemical	O
analysis	O
detected	O
phosphate	B-MAT

# Sentence 105
Contextual	O
records	O
note	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
boundary	I-CON

# Sentence 106
A	O
polished	B-ART
copper	O
mirror	O
was	O
recorded	O

# Sentence 107
Typology	O
links	O
this	O
assemblage	O
to	O
the	O
Post-Gupta	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 108
The	O
survey	O
mapped	O
Kalibangan	B-LOC
mounds	I-LOC

# Sentence 110
Field	O
notes	O
describe	O
a	O
secondary	B-CON
deposit	I-CON

# Sentence 111
A	O
bronze	B-ART
buckle	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 112
Ceramic	O
phases	O
are	O
assigned	O
to	O
the	O
Maurya	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 113
The	O
excavation	O
mapped	O
a	O
site	O
near	O
Sarnath	B-LOC

# Sentence 114
Petrographic	O
analysis	O
identified	O
limestone	B-MAT

# Sentence 115
A	O
terracotta	B-ART
disk	O
was	O
listed	O

# Sentence 116
Radiocarbon	O
calibration	O
gives	O
a	O
range	O
around	O
800	B-PER
BCE	I-PER

# Sentence 117
The	O
team	O
surveyed	O
the	O
Ghaggar	B-LOC
floodplain	I-LOC

# Sentence 118
XRF	O
spectra	O
showed	O
nickel	B-MAT

# Sentence 119
Excavation	O
logs	O
record	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
fill	I-CON

# Sentence 120
A	O
carved	B-ART
seal	O
was	O
catalogued	O

# Sentence 121
Typological	O
comparison	O
places	O
this	O
assemblage	O
in	O
the	O
Kushan	B-PER
period	I-PER

# Sentence 122
The	O
survey	O
documented	O
Lothal	B-LOC

# Sentence 123
Metallurgical	O
tests	O
detected	O
tin	B-MAT

# Sentence 124
Contextual	O
notes	O
mention	O
a	O
trench	B-CON
edge	I-CON

# Sentence 125
A	O
stone	B-ART
celt	O
was	O
photographed	O

# Sentence 126
Ceramic	O
typology	O
is	O
consistent	O
with	O
the	O
Late	B-PER
Harappan	I-PER
phase	I-PER

# Sentence 127
The	O
excavation	O
mapped	O
the	O
Indus	B-LOC
Valley	I-LOC

# Sentence 128
Microscopic	O
analysis	O
identified	O
hematite	B-MAT

# Sentence 129
Field	O
notes	O
record	O
a	O
sealed	B-CON
deposit	I-CON

# Sentence 130
A	O
bronze	B-ART
pin	O
was	O
listed	O

# Sentence 131
Radiocarbon	O
results	O
indicate	O
circa	O
50	B-PER
BCE	I-PER

# Sentence 132
The	O
team	O
surveyed	O
the	O
Ropar	B-LOC
mound	I-LOC

# Sentence 133
Context	O
forms	O
note	O
a	O
posthole	B-CON

# Sentence 134
Typology	O
suggests	O
Early	B-PER
Historic	I-PER

